ISTJ START
Personality: Sensible and dependable and pay attention to detail.
Strengths: Dependable and Systematic
Characteristics: Typically thorough, conscientious, realistic but also systematic and reserved.
Careers & Career Ideas: Like to have clear goals and realistic deadlines, and to work with factual data to solve problems and monitor progress.
Under Stress: Stress triggers can be things that challenge their natural preference for structure and logic.
Relationships: Generally perceived by others as someone who values traditions and is also consistent and orderly.
ISTJ END

ISFJ START
Personality: Considerate and kind individuals with a strong sense of commitment to others.
Strengths: Patient individuals who apply common sense and experience to solving problems for other people.
Characteristics: Practical and patient, but also dependable and loyal
Careers & Career Ideas: Sense of belonging at work and like to work with people who care about and support each other.
Under Stress: In extreme circumstances they tend to be accusatory and pessimistic, tending to think the worst and shut down.
Relationships: Generally dependable and committed to their partners and the groups they are associated with.
ISFJ END


INFJ START
Personality: Compassionate and quietly inspiring; they enjoy helping others grow and develop.
Strengths: Enjoy finding a shared vision for everyone, inspiring others and devising new ways to achieve the vision.
Characteristics: Typically compassionate, idealistic as well as imaginative and visionary.
Careers & Career Ideas: Often enjoy working for organizations with a humanitarian mission and a reputation for integrity.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you may feel physically stressed and intensely angry, with an obsessive focus on certain details and a tendency to overindulge.
Relationships: Generally have a gift to intuitively understand human relationships and complex meanings as well as they often understand emphatically the feelings of their partners.
INFJ END

INTJ START
Personality: Personality types think strategically and see the big picture.
Strengths: Are often able to define a compelling, long-range vision, and can devise innovative solutions to complex problems.
Characteristics: Typically strategic and conceptual as well as innovative, independent and logical. They can also be demanding and but reflective.
Careers & Career Ideas: Tend to enjoy being challenged intellectually and working in an environment that is hard-driving and achievement-oriented.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you may feel physically stressed and intensely angry, with an obsessive focus on certain details and a tendency to overindulge.
Relationships: might find it difficult to engage in social conversations and they tend to be seen as private and reserved. 
INTJ END

ISTP START
Personality: Are calm, efficient, and productive, and are open to new opportunities.
Strengths: Tend to enjoy learning and perfecting a craft through their patient application of skills.
Characteristics: Typically analytical, practical, realistic but also logical and adaptable.
Careers & Career Ideas: like analyzing problems and responding to crises
Under Stress: In extreme circumstances they will tend to feel alienated and upset, and prone to whingeingly and hypersensitivity.
Relationships: Egalitarian and generally tolerant of wide ranges of behavior, but they can surprise others around them by voicing their firm judgements when logical principles are attacked.
ISTP END

ISFP START
Personality: Are sensitive, gentle and attentive to the needs of those around them.
Strengths: Enjoy providing practical help or service to others, as well as bringing people together and facilitating and encouraging their cooperation.
Characteristics: Typically are cooperative, modest and adaptable and also gentle and loyal.
Careers & Career Ideas: Enjoy working at something that is personally meaningful.
Under Stress: In these circumstances they tend to become cynical, depressed, aggressive and prone to acute self-doubt.
Relationships: Prizes the freedom to follow their own path and they enjoy having their own space and setting their own timetables, which they will also give to their partners.
ISFP END

INFP START
Personality: Seek to live in accordance with their inner core of values, and have insight into what is really important to others.
Strengths: Enjoy devising creative solutions to problems, making moral commitments to what they believe in. They enjoy helping others with their growth and inner development to reach their full potential.
Characteristics: Are typically flexible, spontaneous as well as reflective and contained. They are also imaginative and developmental.

Careers & Career Ideas: They enjoy helping others develop and learn and express their creativity through writing or visual arts.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you will tend to become cynical, depressed, aggressive and prone to acute self-doubt.
Relationships: Generally selective and reserved about sharing their deepest feelings and values and can be sometimes difficult to understand. They are seen by their partners as sensitive and introspective.
INFP END

INTP START
Personality: Are logical, analytical, and adaptable, with the ability to respond to new opportunities as they come along.
Strengths: Patient individuals think strategically and are able to build conceptual models to understand complex problems.
Characteristics: Typically independent and detached, who also tends to be challenging and logical as well as skeptical and innovative. 
Careers & Career Ideas: Tend to appreciate occupations in technical and scientific fields, and gain expert knowledge. 
Under Stress: In extreme circumstances you will tend to feel alienated and upset, and prone to whingeingly and hypersensitivity.
Relationships: Can be tolerant of a wide range of behavior of those around them, however they can fail to consider the impact on others of the way or style they express their ideas.
INTP END

ESTP START
Personality: Are energetic, enthusiastic and easily adaptable, and like to make work fun.
Strengths: motivate others by bringing energy into situations.
Characteristics: Typically analytical, outgoing and enthusiastic as well as logical and they tend to be observant and resourceful.
Careers & Career Ideas: Enjoy taking risks, managing crises and putting out fires.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you will tend to be withdrawn, distracted and paranoid, with feelings of chronic anxiety.
Relationships: truly loves life and they immerse themselves in it, their partners see them as adventurous risk-takers as well as pragmatic troubleshooters, however they might be impatient with exploration of relationships.
ESTP END

ESFP START
Personality: Are entertaining, easy-going, sociable people, who like to put others at ease.
Strengths: Tend to be adaptable, friendly, and talkative.
Characteristics: Typically tolerant and spontaneous as well as playful and resourceful. They also tend to be friendly and enthusiastic.
Careers & Career Ideas: Like to make work fun, and to create a spirit of cooperation.
Under Stress: Become stressed in the situations shown in this MBTI stress head illustration. In these circumstances you will tend to be withdrawn, distracted and paranoid, with feelings of chronic anxiety.
Relationships: Generally is a big life-lover who enjoy food, clothes, animals and also the companion of people.
ESFP END

ENFP START
Personality: Are energetic and motivational.
Strengths: Moving quickly from one project to another, ENFPs are willing to consider almost any possibility and often develop multiple solutions to a problem.
Characteristics: Are typically friendly and expressive as well as innovative and energetic.
Careers & Career Ideas: The ideal working environment for ENFPs is one that encourages and rewards creativity, fosters teamwork and offers opportunities to work with a variety of people, particularly in order to support and enlighten them.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you will tend to be over-worried, withdrawn, tunnel-visioned and prone to extreme emotions.
Relationships: Generally is keenly perceptive about people and they also experience feelings of wide ranges as well as intense emotions.
ENFP END

ENTP START
Personality: Are strategic, adaptable, energetic, and enthusiastic.
Strengths: Solve problems creatively and are often innovative in their way of thinking, seeing connections and patterns within a system.
Characteristics: Typically emergent, theoretical, and flexible as well as imaginative and challenging.
Careers & Career Ideas: Prefer to work in a fast-growing, high-energy atmosphere which is characterized by autonomy and the freedom to think differently.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you will tend to be over-worried, withdrawn, tunnel-visioned and prone to extreme emotions.
Relationships: Generally will enjoy a good debate, their conversational style is customarily challenging as well as stimulating.
ENTP END

ESTJ START
Personality: Are analytical, purposeful, decisive and organized.
Strengths: Drive themselves to reach their goal, organizing people and resources in order to achieve it.
Characteristics: Typically responsible and efficient but they can also be assertive as well as logical and realistic.
Careers & Career Ideas: Enjoy setting clear goals and deadlines, and analyzing problems logically.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you will tend to become hypersensitive, emotional, domineering and inflexible.
Relationships: Generally enjoys interacting with others and they take relationship roles seriously and will be keen to fulfil them responsibly.
ESTJ END

ESFJ START
Personality: Conscientious team players who interact closely with others, enjoy a sense of belonging and apply common sense to problems.
Strengths: Tend to be sociable and outgoing, understanding what others need and expressing appreciation for their contributions.
Characteristics: Typically warm and appreciative as well as organized, outgoing and supportive. They are also realistic and loyal.
Careers & Career Ideas: Like to have clear goals and realistic deadlines, and to work with factual data to solve problems and monitor progress.
Under Stress: Work best in an environment that fosters a family-like atmosphere with friendly, caring people.
Relationships: Generally is emotionally highly attuned to others using empathy, understanding their partner's emotional needs and concerns. Their partners view them as responsive and persuasive.
ESFJ END

ENFJ START
Personality: Extraverted, Intuitive, Feeling, and Judging personality traits.
Strengths: Patient individuals able to get the most out of teams by working closely with them, and make decisions that respect and take into account the values of others.
Characteristics: warm, collaborative, and supportive, as well as friendly and organized. They also tend to be persuasive.
Careers & Career Ideas: Enjoy helping others develop new skills, structure their time and meet deadlines.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you will tend to be pessimistic and rigid, and prone to self-doubt and insensitivity.
Relationships: Tend to focus on encouraging the growth of others around them and they quickly understand their emotional needs. Their partners will see them as gracious, expressive and congenial.
ENFJ END

ENTJ START
Personality: Driven, organized, decisive natural leaders.
Strengths: Patient individuals see the big picture and think strategically about the future.
Characteristics: Typically structured and challenging, they also tend to be strategic and questioning.
Careers & Career Ideas: They aren’t afraid to make tough decisions to move forward, and enjoy solving system-level problems.
Under Stress: In these circumstances you will tend to become hypersensitive, emotional, domineering and inflexible.
Relationships: Energized by stimulating interactions with people, which they really enjoy.
ENTJ END
